Ren d'Harnoncourt Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series X: Sarah d'Harnoncourt Donation, 1925-1970s
  - Subseries E: Personal Material
    - Julian Huxley Obituary, 1975; Obituary of Julian Huxley,The New York Times, (2/16/75). (Folder X.E.17)
    - Newspaper clipping about opening of Indian Pueblo Cultural Center, 1977; Clipping from The New York Times(8/28/77), about the opening of an Indian Pueblo Cultural Center in Albuquerque, New Mexico, as a showcase for their traditional arts and crafts. RDH had worked to make this Center a reality. (Folder X.E.18)
    - Color Drawing by Ren d'Harnoncourt, Color drawing by RDH of the letters KHG entwined. (Folder X.E.19)
    - Notes by Sarah d'Harnoncourt, 1971-72; Notes by Sarah d'Harnoncourt, including a list of books with inscriptions by the author to RDH. (Folder X.E.20)
    - Notes by Sarah d'Harnoncourt, n.d.; Notes by Sarah d'Harnoncourt on publications and articles relating to RDHs work with the Indian Arts & Crafts Board. (Folder X.E.21)
    - Anne d'Harnoncourt, 1982; Newspaper clippings about Anne d'Harnoncourt's appointment as director of the Philadelphia Museum of Art,The New York Times(5/26/82), and the Philadelphia Inquirer(6/17/82). Both pieces refer to RDH. Part of letter to Anne d'Harnoncourt from Marga Barr (7/21/82), in which Mrs. Barr writes about RDH. (Folder X.E.22)
    - Mrs. Bliss Parkinson copy of dHoodles booklet, 1968; Copy of dHoodles booklet inscribed to Mrs. Bliss Parkinson (Eliza), and donated by her to the RDH Archive. (Folder X.E.23)
    - Copies of dHoodles Booklet, 1968; Three extra copies of dHoodles booklet. (Folder X.E.24)
    - Red Presentation Box,Drawings and dHoodles, 1968; Volumes I and II of Drawings and dHoodles in red presentation box. Oversize, see box 138. (Folder X.E.25*)
    - Red Presentation Box,Drawings and dHoodles, 1968; Volumes III and IV of Drawings and dHoodles in red presentation box. Oversize, see box 139. (Folder X.E.26*)
    - African Photos, 1968; Photographs of African objects taken by Eliot Elisofon. Oversize, see box 137. (Folder X.E.27*)
    - Awards and Honorary Degrees, Certificates of awards and degrees, incl. corresp. Chevalier de la Legion dHonneur, France (3/13/52) Das Verdienstkreuz, Bonn Government, Germany (1/8/58) Encomienda from the President of the Republic of Peru (4/30/59) Doctor of Humane Letters, Dartmouth College (6/60) Doctor of Humane Letters, Columbia University (3/3/58) Appointment to National Council on the Arts, by President Lyndon B. Johnson (3/2/65) U. S. Department of State Recognition for service in the American Program of the Brussels Universal and International Exhibition (10/58) U. S. Department of State Recognition to MoMA for assistance in the American Program of the Brussels Universal and International Exhibition (10/58) Oversize, see flat file at MoMAQNS. (Folder X.E.28*)
Box and Folder List
File numbers marked by an asterisk (*) indicate oversize material that have been separated to the end of the collection.
Researchers should include the asterisk when issuing a request for such material.
1 I 1-27
2 I 28-49
3 I 50-69
4 II 1-10
5 II 11-25
6 II 26-34
7 II 35-39
8 III 1-5
9 III 6-12
10 III 13-20
11 III 21-25
12 III 26-30
13 III 31-36
14 III 37-42
15 III 43-48
16 III 49-56
17 III 57-62
18 III 63-69
19 III 70-77
20 III 78-83
21 III 84-89
22 III 90-95
23 III 96-102
24 IV 1-10
25 IV 11-21
26 IV 22-31
27 IV 32-38
28 IV 39-49
29 IV 50-66
30 IV 67-83
31 IV 84-100
32 IV 101-113
33 IV 114-123
34 IV 124-134
35 IV 135-147
36 IV 148-163
37 IV 164-186
38 IV 187-211
39 IV 212-231
40 IV 232-250
41 IV 251-263
42 IV 264-273
43 IV 274-285
44 IV 286-296
45 IV 297-307
46 IV 308-321
47 IV 322-330
48 IV 331-337
49 V 1-22
50 V 23-35
51 V 36-48
52 VI 1-8
53 VI 9-15
54 VI 16-26
55 VI 27-42
56 VI 43-48
57 VI 49-68
58 VI 69-79
59 VI 80-91
60 VI 92-98
61 VI 99-107
62 VI 108-116
63 VII 1-12
64 VII 13-16
65 VII 17-23
66 VII 24-30
67 VII 31-35
68 VII 36-44
69 VII 45-53
70 VII 54-57
71 VII 58-67
72 VII 68-77
73 VII 78-85
74 VII 86-91
75 VII 92-97
76 VII 98-104
77 VII 105-109
78 VII 110-114
79 VII 115-121
80 VII 122-128
81 VII 129-134
82 VII 135-142
83 VII 143-150
84 VII 151-158
85 VII 159-164
86 VII 165-174
87 VII 175-183
88 VII 184-189
89 VII 190-195
90 VII 196-200
91 VII 201-208
92 VII 209-221
93 VII 222-226
94 VII 227-235
95 VII 236-242
96 VII 243-249
97 VII 250-255
98 VII 256-262
99 VII 263-273
100 VII 274-277
101 VII 278-280
102 VIII 1-12
103 VIII 13-40
104 VIII 41-55
105 VIII 56-71
106 IX.A 1-23
107 IX.A 24-43
108 IX.A 44-67
109 IX.A 68-88
110 IX.A 89-110
111 IX.A 111-123*
112 IX.B 1-11
113 IX.C 1-15
114 IX.D 1-6
115 IX.D 7-14
116 IX.D 15-24
117 X.A 1-18
118 X.B 1-10
119 X.B 11-12
X.C.1 1-23
120 X.C.1 24-34
X.C.2 1-6
121 X.C.2 7-15
X.C.3 1-6
122 X.C.3 7-11
123 X.C.3 12-19
124 X.C.3 20-28
125 X.C.3 29-35
126 X.C.3 36-38
127 X.C.3 39
128 X.C.3 40-41
X.C.4 1-15*
129 X.C.5 1*-34
130 X.C.5 35-37
X.C.6 1-12
131 X.D 1*-13
132 X.D 14-16
133 X.E 1-28*
134 IX.A 39*
IX.B 10*
135 X.A 16*
136 X.B 6*
X.C.4 9*, 15*
X.C.5 1*, 4*, 5*, 7*, 8*, 10*, 11*, 13*, 16*, 20*, 21*, 25*, 30*
137 X.D 1*, 4*, 15*
X.E 27*
138 X.E 25*
139 X.E 26*